真假老板
The Boss of It All
下面这部电影
Here comes a movie
也许你已经看出有点怪异
and, if it already looks a bit weird
那么坚持住
then hang in there
谁都看出来了
because anyone can see it.
尽管你看到我的反映 相信我
Although you see my reflection, trust me.
这部电影一点反映都不值
this film won't be worth a moment's reflection.
这是部喜剧 因而无害
It's a comedy, and harmless as such.
没有观点的说教或动摇
No preaching or swaying of opinion.
消遣而已
Just a cozy time.
所以为什么不拿艺术来开涮呢
So why not poke fun at artsy-fartsy culture?
这里有个自命不凡的待业演员
So here we have a self-important out-of-work actor
奇迹般地 有了工作
who, by miraculous chance, got a job.
一份很特殊的工作
A very special job.
你好 终于见面了
Hello. So we finally meet.
我是公司总裁
I'm the company president.
我就是公司总裁
我已经把谈合同的代理权交给Ravn先生了
I've given Mr. Ravn power of attorney to conclude the deal.
又见面了 "可选"
Hello again..."Optional."
- Kristoffer 你紧张吗？ - 不
- Kristoffer? Are you nervous? - No.
我们快点办完
Let's get this done.
这是我们的保密协议
It's our non-disclosure agreement.
你说你从未写过戏吗
You said you'd never written for the stage?
我想问为什么
May I ask why?
这个写得既精炼又紧张
This text is succinct and intense.
- 但是涵义丰富 - 真的吗
- But it says far more than it says. - Really?
我本想话越少越好
I had hoped it would say as little as possible.
惩罚条款可能有点重
The sanctions might seem drastic,
但这就是法律
but that's law for you.
最重要的是
The main thing is that
这件事你得保密
you keep this a secret.
- 保密 - 但你肯定习惯了
- Secret? - But you're used to that.
你总不能在舞台上打死人 然后跟观众说 我在演戏而已
You don't shoot someone on stage and tell the crowd: "I'm only acting."
我不知道
I don't know.
这很像是 一个甘比尼笔下的反角色 会说的话
That particular statement applies to many of Gambini's anti-characters.
- 我是你的人 Ravn - 很好
- I'm your man, Ravn. - Great.
你演的是老板
You're playing the boss.
我有点出风头
I'm in a bit of a pinch
因为真正的老板…
because the real boss is...
不在
not accessible.
我们得上场了 那些冰岛人急坏了
We must act now. The Icelanders are so damn pushy.
用不了多久的
It won't take too long,
你能挣一大笔
so you'll be making quite a bundle,
考虑到你正失业
seeing as you're not working.
签在这里
Sign here.
我不是 为了工作才工作的
I don't keep busy... just to be busy.
又没有违法之类的
It's not illegal or anything!
违不违法 我不在乎
Legal or illegal, I don't care.
我是个演员 角色就是我的法律 剧本就是我的法庭
I'm an actor. The character is my law. And the script is my court.
法庭
Court?
我们祈祷别走到那一步吧
Let's pray it never gets that far.
很好 你的钱
Excellent... Your money.
你额头上是什么？
What's that on your forehead?
煤灰
Soot.
我一直信赖甘比尼 从不出错
I always rely on Gambini. You can't go wrong.
《挨饿的猫》
The Hanged Cat?
烟囱工的独白 《没有烟囱的城市》里的
The chimney sweep's monologue, from A Town without Chimneys.
- 你知道吗 - 我只知道《猫老大》
- You know it? - I only know Top Cat.
"我已被迫 走了很远 来到这个城市"
"I have traveled far, and with reluctance, to this town."
我们总裁不能沾着煤灰 在额头上
Our president doesn't have soot... on his forehead.
一个角色不能做的事
The things a character doesn't have...
定义了他是谁
define him more than what he has.
戏剧的展开 正是始于剧本的边界
Theater begins to unfold itself at the point where it ends.
别让我紧张 Kristoffer
Don't make me nervous, Kristoffer.
我们简单点
Let's keep it simple.
我只是用角色向甘比尼小小地致敬
I'll just endow my character with a small tribute to Gambini.
好吧
Fine!
没什么区别 你就演一小会儿
It won't make any difference. You're only the boss for a moment.
还有这些停顿
Then there's the pauses...
是理解一部戏的关键
So vital to our understanding.
他甚至可以一句话都不说
He could actually not say anything at all.
你必须得把上面这些说出来
You have to say what's on the page.
不然有什么意义
Otherwise, what's the point?
- 就上面这些 - 就上面这些
- Just what's on the page. - Just what's on the page.
你好 终于见面了 我是公司总裁
Hello. So we finally meet. I'm the company president.
我终于找到他了
I finally tracked him down.
这是Finnur
This is Finnur...
"Finor"
This is Finor...
你好 终于见面了 我是公司总裁
"Hello. So we finally meet.
I'm the company president."
你好 终于见面了 我是公司总裁
Hello. So we finally meet.
I'm the company president.
是 两位先生都是公司总裁
Yes, both you gents
are indeed company presidents.
但是属于两个不同公司
But for two different companies.
为什么丹麦人话这么多
"Why do Danes talk so much?
怪不得这个民族的智力发展 200年前就止步了
"No wonder this country came to
a halt intellectually 200 years ago.
不是啰里啰唆 就是多愁善感得直滴水
"They yak away or are drippingly sentimental.
剩下的时间就在傻笑
"The rest of the time they giggle."
拜托快点开始吧 Ravn
"Let's for God's sake get started, Mr. Ravn."
尊敬的总裁先生
Dear Mr. President -
我是指我们的总裁
and I'm referring to
our own little president -
有不止一位总裁在这儿挺好
We're happy just to have a president.
我想说的是
I want to say the following...
我们总裁
Our president -
要求不参与谈判
has requested to be kept out of the negotiations.
我说的对吧
Did I get that right?
最主要的是价位
The price is our top priority.
我们已经商量好了
And we've already agreed on it.
我已经 -
I have...
将 -
turned over...
代 - 理 -
power...
权 -
of attorney...
授 - 予 -
to Mr...
Ravn
Ravn.
不好意思
I'm sorry...
我没太听懂
I didn't quite get that.
你的停顿把我弄糊涂了
The pauses confused me.
你可以快点重复一遍吗
Would you mind repeating it a bit quicker?
我已经将代理权授予Ravn
I have turned over
power of attorney to Mr. Ravn.
我们总裁一旦决定 就不可能改变心意了
Once our president's mind is made up, no amount of ruckus can change it.
总裁先生
Mr. President...
这些总裁啊
All these presidents!
我们是不是该叫 "丹麦总裁"
Should we call ours "the Danish president"?
算了 冰岛或者丹麦 都一样
Icelandic or Danish... Same thing!
被冰岛占领了400年
400 jolly years under Icelandic rule.
恰恰相反
It was the other way round.
对我们来讲可不是那样
It sure as hell didn't feel that way to us.
不
No.
好了 我要回美国去了
Well, I better get back to the States.
就算12号由我来签约 那也是一样的
Just because I'll sign on the 12th doesn't make it less fun.
该死的丹麦佬 别想就这么跑掉
"You fucking Danes
aren't getting off that lightly.
光说不干 该死的奴隶主
"It's all talk, fucking slave drivers!
幸好史诗里教过我们
"Fortunately the sagas left us these wise words:
"同配角打交道 一事无成"
"He who deals with stooges deals with nobody."
再见
Goodbye.
Finnur
Finnur!
我坚持在12号必须
"I insist that the president
由总裁来和我商谈 而不是他的喽啰
"deal with me on the 12th. Not his stooge.
那一周他必须待在这儿 否则免谈
"He'll have to stay home that week or there's no deal.
我的律师会联系你
"You'll be hearing from my lawyer."
再见了
Bye then...
"可选"
"Optional."
你好 终于见面了 我是公司总裁
Hello. So we finally meet. I'm the company president.
操 不该让他们看见你
Shit! They weren't supposed to see you.
消息会传遍的
Word will spread like wildfire.
他们看得出来我不是真的
They could tell I wasn't for real.
他们没来得及告诉Finnur
They had no time to tell Finnur...
不是这个问题
That's not the problem.
他们惊讶是因为 他们以为你就是真的总裁
They looked shocked because they thought you were the real president.
好吧 我是演得很好
Well, I did play him well.
尽管你没给我多少素材
Although you didn't give me much to work with.
只要表演是一流的
If the performance is topnotch
外形相似就不那么重要了
physical resemblance has less significance.
和这十年的总裁 外形是否相似无关紧要
The physical resemblance with their president of ten years is irrelevant.
他们从来没见过他
They've never seen him.
- 从来没见过 - 没有
- Never seen him? - No.
我没明白
I don't quite get it.
要不是我是这么个懦夫
If I wasn't such a wuss.
公司得有总裁  我不是这块料
Companies need presidents. I didn't have it in me.
我没法把自己看成个总裁
I couldn't see myself as one.
所以我创办公司时
So when I started the company
告诉他们 我也只是个员工
I told them I was an employee.
说总裁有多家公司 住在美国
That the president was tending to his companies and lived in the States.
我知道这很古怪 很可疑
I know it's strange and suspicious.
一个我编出来的老板 Kristoffer
A boss that I invented, Kristoffer.
一直挺好 除非有人想找他谈
It was fine as long as no one wanted to talk to him.
现在又来了个该死的冰岛人 他们谁也信不过
Then that fucking Icelander came along. They don't trust anyone.
古怪
Strange...
甘比尼也被人说古怪
They called Gambini strange too.
听着
Look...
我说过了我是你的人
I told you I was your man.
而且我 不是随便什么人
I am... And not just any man.
我是个演员
I'm an actor.
要解决你的问题 需要的正是这个
That's exactly what you need to make your world work.
就一个礼拜 我拟份合同
It's only a week. I'll write a contract.
用不着
No need.
这是我的爱好
It's a hobby of mine.
这件事对公司非常关键
This deal is vital to the company.
有一丁点怀疑
The slightest doubt...
要分辨观众心中的怀疑 我太有经验了
I have considerable training in sensing doubt in the minds of my audience.
你得见见公司员工
You'll have to meet the staff.
好 这是工作需要
Yeah. Being seen is part of the job.
要是你说出去 你就死定了
If you talk, I'll slaughter you!
少大惊小怪
Stop fussing.
Heidi 我是Ravn 你可以把六位高管叫过来吗
Heidi A? Would you get the six seniors together?
我想让你们见个人
I want you to meet someone special.
他们六个是和我一同起步的人
They're the six I started out with.
终于来了 大老板
Here at last...
The boss of it all.
他在日程里抽出了一周 待在丹麦和我们一起
He took a week out of his schedule to be with us in Denmark.
也许因为他骨子里仍然 是个丹麦人
Probably because deep down inside he's... Danish.
也许他觉得他
And perhaps he feels he has...
不能说"抛弃" 但确实"忽视"了我们分部
maybe not abandoned, but neglected our little branch.
是 很好理解
Yes, that's understandable.
很
That's...
很好理解
That's understandable.
是的 是很好理解
Yes, that is understandable.
那你们要聊的应该很多
So there's lots for you to talk about.
我想我就 所谓的 "夹着尾巴"
I guess I'll stick my tail between my legs, as they say...
溜回办公室去了
and scoot on back to my office.
有什么要问吗
Any questions?
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
- 我叫什么 - 对
- My name? - Yes.
除了"大老板" 没人叫过你别的
No one's ever called you anything but "the boss of it all."
有的姑娘有幸邮件收到过你的指示
Some of the girls had the honor of getting emails with specific details.
是
Yeah.
让我说清楚 我是随机
Let me make it clear that it's been at random,
挑选这几年直接联系的人的
who I needed to write directly to over the years.
没有任何个人偏好
There's no personal preference there.
天啊
Holy smoke...
真得小心点
One does have to be careful.
他叫Svend
His name is Svend.
Svend E.
我的邮件上写着的
That's what my emails said.
E什么
What does the E stand for?
我没写吗 Ravn没说过
Didn't I write that? Ravn didn't say?
十年了 从来没
For ten years? Never, ever?!
这是好事 因为这就是说
That's good news. Because that means...
我可以告诉你们 我
I can tell you that I have a name I'm very partial to...
喜欢的名字
and proud of.
Ecker
Ecker...
Eckers
Eckers...
berg
berg...
Svend Eckersberg
Svend Eckersberg.
那我应该叫你
And what should I call you?
Gorm想叫你Svend
Gorm wants to call you Svend.
Gorm
Gorm...
想叫我什么都行
may call me whatever he likes.
Gorm甚至可以叫我Kristoffer 他想的话
Gorm may even call me Kristoffer, if he likes.
Kristoffer 为什么要叫那个
Why should he call you Kristoffer?
不
No
为什么呢 到底为了什么呢
Why on earth should he? Why in the world should he?
请叫我Svend就好
By all means, call me Svend.
好的 Svend
OK, Svend.
我想说件事
I'd like to say one thing.
- 乡下的秋天太阴郁了 - Gorm 别
- Autumn in the country is muggy. - Gorm, don't.
真是太阴郁了 我告诉你
Real muggy! I want you to know that.
人们通常会说秋天有种清新感
People generally think autumn has a freshness to it.
别 Gorm
No, Gorm!
你够了吗
Are you done now? Huh?!
没事
Everything's cool.
你够了吗
Are you done?
嗯 对不起
Yeah. Sorry, sorry.
一点事都没有
Everything is perfectly fine.
停下
Stop it!
打得不轻啊
Boy, that's nasty.
恐怕你得道个歉
I'm afraid you'll have to apologize.
我跟他道歉
Should I apologize to him?!
别忘了明天还有技术会议呢
Don't forget the tech conference tomorrow.
技术会议
Tech conference...
Ravn
Ravn...
他们全都疯了
They're all completely insane.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
到外面 我会叫你
On neutral ground! I'll call you.
好吧
OK.
如果
If...
比如说 我的角色名叫Svend
my character's name is Svend, for example,
那我想知道
then I'd like to know.
我只是希望能有所准备
I just want to be in the loop.
当然了
Sure.
名字根本无所谓
The names didn't really matter.
无所谓
Didn't really matter?
Gorm是个乡下孩子 他有时候有点抑郁
Gorm is a country boy. He sometimes suffers from rural depression.
但是对于Brooker5他是个奇才
But he's a wizard with Brooker 5.
那是什么玩意
What the hell is that?
Brooker5
Brooker 5?
我们的旗舰 销量冠军 我们就是靠它起家的
Our flagship, our biggest seller. That's what we started out with.
我的角色不喜欢大哭 大叫 打人
My character doesn't like when they cry, shout or hit.
我的私人空间受到了侵犯
My personal space has been violated.
我一定得掌控住
I must insist on control.
他们得顺从
They must be subdued.
那六个高管可能有点麻烦
The six seniors can be a bit of a hassle.
他们是公司的创新主力
They're the creative bunch in the firm.
我不了解演员们的心理
I don't know about the psychology of actors...
不过我想应该差不多的
but I imagine it's similar.
真有那么糟糕
So things are that bad?
我很喜欢他们 但他们很难打交道
I love them dearly. Although they have knocked me around a bit.
不可能比1992年在斯拉格斯那次更糟了
It can't be as bad as Slagelse in 1992.
尽管演出后我还是驳倒了那个女观众
Though I did talk the women ticket holders down after the show.
我并不知道斯拉格斯也有戏剧
I didn't know Slagelse had a theater.
他们没有 艺术上讲
And they didn't, artistically speaking.
怎么了 什么事
What's wrong? What was that?
那是我疏远的表情
My mournful and remote look.
肯定挺吓人的
It must terrify people.
是 挺有用的
Yes, it's effective.
那六个高管比我想的更强硬
The six seniors were more feisty than I'd expected.
那个技术会议听着很可怕
This tech conference sounds ominous.
告诉我你们是做什么的 我好学点行话
Tell me about what you do, so I can learn the lingo.
IT
IT.
IT?
那个不可能速成
That's impossible to grasp!
我根本没机会
I don't stand a chance.
幸亏你是个好演员
Good thing you're such a good actor.
现在你有准备了
You're prepared now.
压制他们
Subdue them.
掌控住
Take control.
好吗
All right?
哇
Wow...
复印机启动的时候 是挺吓人的
It's quite a shocker when the copy machine starts.
幸好不是那么频繁
Luckily it's not that often.
每天也就一千次
Only a thousand times a day.
今天乡下天气怎么样
How's the weather out in the country today?
好吧 要我估计
Well, let's just assume
就和整个国家一样寒冷
that it's wintry like it is throughout the country.
在找你的办公室
Looking for your office?
我估计办公室会比走廊安全些
I figured the office would be a safer bet than the corridors.
安全 什么意思
Safer?What do you mean?
好让大家找得到我 既然我极少在这儿
So people can find me. Since I'm here rather seldom.
那你想见见他们吗
So you want to see them?
我告诉他们等着 我会传达到的
I told them to wait. I'll pass it on.
谢谢
Thanks.
Jokumsen在外面等着呢
Jokumsen is waiting outside.
我不知道他怎么发现你在这儿的
I don't know how he found out you were here.
是DB7补丁的缺陷清单的事
It's the deficiency list for the DB 7 patch.
我很怀疑从上次投诉之后 他的心情会有所好转
I doubt if he's lightened up since he last complained.
要把Jokumsen推迟到技术会议之后吗
Should we push Jokumsen till after the tech conference?
不好意思
Sorry.
你不在时 它就是老板来着
He's acted as our boss when the boss wasn't here.
我们先从管理的愿景开始
We start off with the management's visions.
我想多了解一点愿景
I'd like to hear more about the visions.
我研究了以往的企业理念
I studied the old corporate philosophy.
- 企业理念 - 是的
- Corporate philosophy? - Yeah.
比如说 有些技术和战略手段不是特别清晰
And, as such, certain technical and strategic measures seem most unclear.
事务级别 为什么不
Transaction hierarchy... Why not?
80-20原则
The 80:20 rule.
事务级别… 为什么不 ?!
80-20原则 !
敏捷开发
Agile development.
这只是些基本的东西
That's just a minor part of the terms necessary
对于合格的IT的定义来说
to define IT at an acceptable level.
除了这些该死的术语
Aside from those fucking terms,
老板对于事务级别的定义是什么
what's the boss' definition of transaction hierarchy?
还有80-20原则 可能是我走神了 什么意思
And the 80:20 rule? Maybe I dozed off, but what is it?
"敏捷开发"有七八种不同解读
"Agile development" is defined in seven or eight different ways.
你是怎么定义的
How would you define it?
定义…
Define...
"规定" 我该说是
"Dictate," I'm tempted to say.
"定义"和"规定"之间存在细微的差别
There is a very fine line between defining and dictating.
全在于老板是不是想要"规定"
And it all boils down to whether the boss wants to dictate.
或者在于老板对公司是做什么的 有多少概念
Or rather whether the boss has any idea what we do in this company.
你对公司是做什么的 又有多少概念
Or whether you have any idea what we do at this company.
- 我不是那个意思 - 是吗
- I should certainly say so. - No?
那是什么
What, then?
什么
- What?
- 我们是做什么的 - 对
- What we do? - Yeah.
- 你都没准备个报告吗 - 关于我们做什么
- Didn't you prepare a presentation? - What do we do?
就那些…
- This and that. - Yes.
- 概括吗 - 对 比如
- In general? - Yes, for example.
嗨
Hi, everyone.
我有点事要讲
I just have a practical announcement.
噢Nalle 怎么愁眉苦脸的
Oh, Nalle... Such a pouty face.
来吧
Come on.
来抱抱
And a big hug.
你要讲的是什么事 Ravn
What was the practical nature of your announcement, Ravn?
去库伦的旅行…
The trip to Kullen..
取消了
is off.
但是 我们从去年开始就没去成
But we were going because we didn't go last year.
谁能告诉我… 什么… 那个…
Can anybody tell me... what... that?
- 闭嘴吧 Spencer - 再接再厉 Spencer
- Keep quiet, Spencer. - Work on it.
恐怕这个是上头决定的
I am afraid the decision came from above.
我知道这意味着福利缩水
I know it reflects a hard policy about perks.
我相信一定是有理由的
I'm sure there's a perfectly good reason.
我们去不了 是因为大老板说的
The reason we're not going is because the boss of it all says so.
"因为大老板说的" 真他妈老套
"Because the boss of it all says so." That's a fucking old line.
我们六个干嘛不直接带着Brooker5走人算了
Why don't the six of us just take our rights to Brooker 5 and leave?
- 友好一点 Gorm - 但你对我们可一点不友好
- Be nice, Gorm. - But you're not nice to us.
我们都这么想 没有这个该死的大老板会好得多
We all agree we'd be far better off without the fucking boss of it all.
别把好气氛破坏了 都是我的错
Let's not dampen the good mood. It's my fault.
这次会议不是为了争论大老板是否强硬的
This conference is not for debating whether the boss is a hard-ass or not.
我们听听Svend怎么说
Let's hear what Svend has to say.
Svend 来吧 Svend
Svend? Come on, Svend!
- 我们会看看销售报表 - 嗯
- We usually get the sales figures. - Yeah.
虽然通常不是在技术会议上
Though not at the tech conference,
你可以跟我们说说 如果你看过了的话
Maybe you can give us an idea, if you've seen them.
我当然看过了
Of course I have seen them.
那你觉得怎么样
So how do they look?
就是泡屎
They're shit.
终于说开了
Now it's finally out.
就是泡屎
They're shit.
就是泡尿
They're piss.
就是泔水
They're pig swill.
我们得调转方向
We need to turn this ship round!
那些报表得改头换面
Those figures had better look completely different.
现在终于说出来了
Now it's out in the open.
没事 Mette
There, Mette.
但是在邮件里你说挺好啊
But the figures look fine in your mails.
- 是Mette说挺好 - 对啊
- Did Mette say they were fine? - Yeah.
我只能说 Mette
All I can say, Mette,
就是还不够好
is that they aren't good enough.
远远 远远不够 Mette
Far, far from it, Mette.
可怜的Mette又要哭了
Now poor Mette is crying again.
没事的 Mette
There, Mette.
就是些数字而已
They're just numbers.
他们在外面排着
They are lined up outside.
你想见Lise Spencer 还是Jokumsen
You want to see Lise and Spencer, or Jokumsen?
除了Jokumsen谁都行 他的投诉很合理
Anyone but Jokumsen. His complaint seems legitimate.
Lise是我们的HR代表
Lise is our HR representative.
当然了 不然呢
Sure, why not?
Spencer有事要说
Spencer has something to say.
窝们…布会…栽…
We will work longer...
"我们不会"
"We will"
不会…栽…
No longer
"不会再"
"No longer"
我们不会再…忍受…介样的…
We will no longer... accept... thighs...
"这样的"
"These"
供作缓解
working conditions.
既然你说不好 还是让我来说容易点
It's easier for me to say it when you can't say it properly.
他是说 "工作环境"
He means "working conditions."
我们的工作环境糟透了 还有人事政策
Our working conditions are dreadful. So is the personnel policy.
其他公司都有津贴 奖金
Other companies have perks.
这有个清单
Here's a list.
你介意回避一下吗 Heidi
Would you mind leaving, Heidi?
到外面去
All the way out.
所以你是属于
So you are affiliated with...
某个帮派的
certain biker circles.
我还天真地以为
I would be naive to think
他们的把戏仅限于小店员中间
their racket is limited to small shopkeepers.
有"地狱游侠"给你们撑腰
With the Hell's Angels up your sleeve,
就可以提要求了
your demands require a different approach.
但是别声张
But keep quiet about it.
HR
HR 人力资源
HR. Human Resources.
你去美国太久
You've been in the States so long,
连"人力资源" 都忘了 我给你查下英文
you can't remember what it means.
I'll look it up for you in English.
你可以告诉我
You can tell me.
可以直说
You can fess up.
我和大家谈过了
I discussed it with the others.
我们觉得你的说服力成问题
We think you have a credibility problem.
你的性格出卖了你
Your personality gives you away.
那根本不是你
You're not who you pretend to be.
我觉得你应该说出真相
I think you should come clean.
你觉得这样好吗
You think that's a wise thing to do?
在这种时候
at this point?
你真这么想
You think so?
是
Yes.
没什么差别 你太明显了
It wouldn't change much. You're so transparent.
你的台词毫无说服力
All your lines really lack cred.
从头到尾演得都很烂
It's lousy acting from start to finish.
- 我的台词没说服力 - 对
- My lines lack cred? - Yeah.
"你太过了"
"You are too much!"
还有 "演得很烂"
Let's not forget "lousy acting."
那正是观众动容的时候
That's when audiences are shook up.
他们难道不懂当今喜剧的重点
Don't they get that the point of comedy nowadays
正在于喜剧的揭穿吗
is to reveal the comedy?
灾难已经发生 现在已经是灾后了
Disaster has already struck. It's all in the aftermath.
人们只想要可信 想要自然
People just want things to be credible and natural.
饶了我吧
Give me a fucking break!
你的说服力有问题
You have a credibility problem.
不 我没有
No, I don't.
- 你有 - 我没有
- Yes, you do. - No, I don't.
我对你了解不多 但我知道你不是谁
I don't know much about you, but I know what you aren't.
那就告诉我 我他妈不是谁
Then tell me what I'm not, for fuck's sake!
基佬
Gay.
- 基佬 - 对 基佬
- Gay? - Yes, gay.
你想让我以为你是同性恋倒还好
It's not so much that you try to make me think you're gay,
但你还装作不知道"IT"什么意思
but you also pretend to be oblivious to IT...
还有"管理"
management...
对了 "人力资源"
and even Human Resources.
"地狱游侠"
Hell's Angels.
拜托
Honestly!
你当然是个专家 不然怎么做到这么大
Of course you're an expert, otherwise you would never have made it this big.
对吗
Am I right?
对
Yeah.
为什么你会觉得
Why would you think I...
我是基佬
I was gay?
你发给我那些邮件 和我保持距离
All those emails you sent me, distancing yourself from me.
然后你叫Ravn暗示我
And you got Ravn to plant the idea.
这样对我有什么好处
What pleasure would I get from that?
就像你假装业务上的白痴一样
The same you get from looking like a complete jackass, professionally.
想逗趣 或者让我们可怜你
To seem interesting or make us feel sorry for you.
这个你可说对了
You hit home with that one.
就是那个
The thing about...
假装
pretending...
根本不懂IT
to be completely oblivious to IT,
这有点牵强了 我承认
it was a bit naive, I admit.
但我确实是基佬
But I am gay.
你看着一点也不像基佬
You don't seem gay at all.
有些人是不像
That's how some of us are.
这不是为了说服你
And it's not to win you over.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
我天生就是个捅屁股的
I've been a cornholer since birth.
没什么理由
There is no explanation for it.
但捅屁股总比干举着强
But rather a poop pusher than a dry old stick.
我能告诉你你为什么喜欢男人
I can explain why you've always gone for men.
你还没遇到对的女人
You haven't met the right woman yet.
到外面来 马上
On neutral ground, ASAP.
我受够了在黑暗中摸索了
I'm exhausted, fumbling in the dark.
什么都控制不了
No control whatsoever.
我要是知道我都说过写过什么 会轻松些
It would be easier if I knew what I had said or written in my past.
- 我是说 基佬 - 基佬
I mean, gay! Gay?
你可以告诉我的
You could have told me.
操 Ravn
Dammit, Ravn!
你说得对
You're right.
但只有Lise的总裁是基佬
But only Lise's president is gay.
你跟每个人说得不一样
You told them different things?!
我听到了
I hear you.
- 你跟他们说得各不相同 - 我听懂了
- You told them different things? - I understand the question.
你是彻底的白痴吗
Are you a complete idiot?
- 这能制造好的共鸣 - 好的共鸣
- It created a good vibe. - A good vibe?
每个人都觉得他
Everyone felt he...
亲近自己
belonged to them.
某种程度上确实是的
And in that sense, he did.
还有那堆IT的玩意 我搞不懂
And that IT shit? I don't get it.
我也是
Me neither.
你做得很好
You're doing great.
- 你觉得 - 是
- You think? - Yeah.
再坚持几天
Stick it out a couple of more days.
听我的 Kristoffer
Take my advice, Kristoffer.
别太严肃了
Don't take it so seriously.
控制之类的 可能挺好的
All that stuff about controlling and subduing is probably fine,
但还是不要那样更简单
but it's easier not to.
让观众自己来
Make the audience do the work.
那样你就不会有压力了
Then you won't feel so stressed out.
你就说 "是"
Just say yes.
他们来找你 "是"
When they come to you - "Yes."
可能不太艺术 但是好使
Maybe not so artistic, but it works.
- 说"是" - 说"是"
- Say yes? - Say yes!
但那是即兴剧
But that's improvisational theater.
好比有个混蛋突发奇想 要穿裙子
Like when some jackass gets it into his head he should put on a dress,
我们也得鼓掌
and we all have to applaud it.
甘比尼不信这个
Gambini didn't believe in it.
对他来说 即兴是对客厅剧的低头
To him, improvisation was just kowtowing to the parlor drama.
甘比尼是头一个看穿易卜生的
Gambini was one of the first to see through lbsen.
易卜生是个蠢货
Ibsen was a moron!
太古板 无力扼住灾难的咽喉
Too prim to grab disaster by the throat.
怎么不直接改成肥皂剧算了
Why not go straight to soap?
那些多愁善感和该死的陈词滥调
With all its sentimentality and fucking clichés.
"这是再见  不是永别"
"This is not adieu, but au revoir!"
类似的废话
Or shit like that.'
那是放屁
It's bull.
- 是放屁 - 是 放屁
- It's bull. - Sure. Bull.
- 放屁 - 是
- Bull! - Sure.
放松
Calm down.
对不起 你最懂了
I'm sorry. You know best.
这是你的角色和想法
It's your character and idea.
想法就是上帝
And the idea is God.
连希特勒也不例外
Even Hitler's.
要是你想要即兴剧和群体剧
If you want improvisation and group theater...
我就满足你
I'll give it to you.
我就说是 一直说是
I'll say yes. Say yes.
直到你不想听为止
Until you choke on it. Yes.
但是别对Jokumsen说
But not to Jokumsen.
他那个合理的投诉已经六年了
He has had a legitimate complaint for six years.
- 他六年前怎么不来呢 - 他来了
- Why didn't he come six years ago? - He did.
但是那天大老板不在
But the boss of it all wasn't in that day.
我懂了
Oh, I see.
那些IT术语呢
And about those IT terms?
他们说"外包"的时候 是想说"外移"
When they say "outsourcing," they mean "offshoring."
就这么简单
Piece of cake.
cLib模块的性能问题比我们想的要更广
The cLib module performance issues are more extensive than we thought.
成为了整个系统的瓶颈
Bottlenecks throughout the system.
我们应该在客户端加入更多验证
We should put far more validations client-side.
外包是个好主意 但是cLib模块
Outsourcing is very tempting, but as the cLib module...
不好意思
Excuse me.
你是说 "外移"
You mean... offshoring.
你说"外包" 但你是想说"外移"
You said outsourcing, but you mean offshoring.
没错
Of course.
谢谢 Svend
Thank you, Svend.
大老板怎么说
What does the boss of it all say?
Nalle和Mette取得许可了吗
Do Nalle and Mette get a green light?
你是说 是或否
You mean yes or no?
我想我知道会怎么说
I think I can answer that.
我们都知道 "便宜三分之一我们就继续"
We all can, "A third cheaper and we go ahead."
Nalle猜得对吗
Is Nalle right in his assumption?
是的
Yes.
大老板说话了
The boss of it all has spoken.
你就非得 给Nalle难堪
You just had to... take Nalle down a peg.
在大家面前训斥他
Rap his knuckles with everyone watching.
你真是个混蛋
You're a real bastard.
是的
Yes.
起来啦
Upsy-daisy.
来抱抱
And a big hug.
真可爱 是不是 像个小孩
Cute, right? Like a little baby.
不 小孩意味着生育
No, wait, babies mean procreation,
那就涉及到和异性上床
and that entails screwing members of the opposite sex.
如果你有
If you have...
任何问题
any questions,
或者要求找我
or requests of me,
我的答复会是 "是的"
then the answer might be yes.
有什么我能说的吗 或者任何人
Is there anything I can say? Or that anyone can say?
他们会说
They might say,
是的
yes.
是的 是的 是的
Or yes, yes, yes.
我受够了 Svend 听到了吗
I've had it, Svend. You read me?
是
Yes.
听到最好 你那些基佬之类的鬼话
You better! All your gay crap.
有男人打我主意的时候 我很清楚
I know when a man lusts after me.
是
Yes.
你真能戏弄人
You're such a tease.
是
Yes.
那些个邮件
All those emails.
"对Ravn好点 Lise 关照Ravn"
"Be nice to Ravn, Lise. Take care of Ravn."
都是为了钓我
They were meant to get me going.
是
Yes.
那些基佬之类的胡闹也全都是
That faggy farce is all very well,
为了钓大鱼
but there are better fish to fry.
我没意见
Fine by me.
是
Yes.
只要是你说了算就行 是吗
As long as you're in control, right?
是
Yes.
就这里 就现在 越快越好
Right here, right now. The sooner the better.
是
Yes.
你这个沙文主义公猪
You male chauvinist pig.
是
Yes.
来个像样的口活 不然没得操
There will be no fucking till you get a proper blow-job.
然后我趴到桌子上去 就得这样
And now, over the desk I go. That's just the way it is.
是
Yes.
是吗
Right?
你最喜欢的就是
You like it best...
我什么都没得选
when I have no say in the matter.
你别弄错了 我可有两个洞
Don't let it confuse you, but I have two holes.
是
Yes.
对
Right.
这就是为什么
So that's why...
他们管你叫大老板
they call you the boss of it all.
你这个混蛋
You are a bastard.
是
Yes.
- 是 - 是是是是是
- Yes. - Yes, yes, yes.
你就只会说这个
Is that all you can say?!
你了解甘比尼吗
Are you familiar with Gambini?
谁
Who?
你看起来累了
You look tired.
我跟Jokumsen说 他今天不能见你
I told Jokumsen he couldn't see you today.
我让他下周再来试试 可以吧
I told him to try again next week. Hope that's all right.
行 那时候我就不在了
That's fine, 'cause I won't be here.
你又要走
Are you leaving again?
对了
By the way,
谢谢你那些问候 从世界各地
thanks for all your greetings from round the world.
对我很有意义
They meant a lot to me.
我全都回复了
And I've replied to all of them.
除了一次
Apart from one.
是的
Yes.
是 没错
Yes, that's right.
那次你没有回
There was one you didn't reply to.
为什么没
Why didn't you?
你要现在谈这个
You want to talk about it now?
是 我在这呢
Yes. I'm here now.
确实
That's true.
你总是在开玩笑
You're always making jokes about everything.
有时候让我困惑 分不清你是不是在开玩笑
Sometimes it confuses me. I can't tell if you are joking.
为什么你会觉得那是个玩笑
Why would you think it was a joke?
不大可能是别的什么
It could hardly be anything else.
如果不是玩笑 你会怎么说
If it hadn't been a joke, what would you have said?
我想你知道的
I think you know.
不 所以我才问
No. That's why I am asking.
如果不是个玩笑
If it wasn't a joke...
我会说是的
...I would have said yes.
真是疯了 考虑到我们几乎不熟
That's nuts, seeing as we hardly know each other.
你看起来并不激动
You don't seem thrilled about my yes.
对不起 我太傻了
Sorry. How stupid of me.
太丢人了
This is embarrassing.
所以我才没回复
That's why I didn't reply.
那当然是个玩笑
Of course it was a joke.
是啊 很好笑
Yes, and it's funny.
我太傻了 还以为你认真的
I'm so stupid, I thought you meant it.
对不起 我脸都红了
Sorry. I'm going all red.
我觉得
I think that...
你会说是的 这很好
it's great that you would have said yes.
不是每个人都会的 我敬佩你
Not everyone would. I respect you for it.
天啊 很好
My goodness. Great.
我们就忘了吧好吗
Can we just forget about it?
不敢相信我居然这么含糊 让你疑惑了
I can't believe I was so ambiguous that you were in doubt.
这不像是我 不是我的角色
It's not like me. It's not in character.
有时我们问问看是为了
Sometimes we ask questions in jest that we'd like an answer to,
以防有一天真的要问
in case we ever ask for real.
我还以为是有些实情在
I just thought there were real feelings there.
拜托
Come on!
你以为我会这样子打掩护吗
You think I'd cover my bets like that?
出于害怕去骗取答复
And fish for an answer out of fear?
听着像大老板做的事吗
Does that sound like the boss of it all?
做人讲信用 做老板更讲信用
A man is a man, a word is a word, and a boss is a goddamn boss.
我不是靠着说大话起家的
I didn't build an empire by farting around like that.
Heidi A. 那封邮件我记得很清楚
Heidi A. I remember that mail clearly.
你问我是不是认真的 我会说是的
If you ask me whether I meant it, the answer is yes.
仍然算数
And the question still stands.
就这样
Damn right!
噢就对了
"Oh" is right.
- 我好开心 - 你开心我就开心
- I'm so happy. - If you're happy, I'm happy.
你不会只是为了阻止我辞职的吧
It wasn't just to keep me from quitting?
当然不是 这有什么关系
Of course not. What does that have to do with it?
我确实没辞职 留下来了
And I didn't quit. I stayed with you.
- 确实 - 主要是因为你的邮件
- You did. - Mainly because of your email.
是的 我想该下班了 即便是老板
Yes, and I think it's time to knock off, even for the boss.
我很高兴这个解决使双方都满意了
I'm glad we got that little matter sorted to our mutual satisfaction.
你看起来还在烦恼什么
You look like something is bugging you again.
- 都会好起来的 - 我只是很高兴你是认真的
- Everything will be fine. - I'm just so happy you meant it.
尤其鉴于你对我的了解如此之少
Especially considering how little you know about me.
你没什么想问我的吗
Isn't there anything you'd like to ask me?
当然有了 Heidi A.
Of course there is, Heidi A.
A代表什么 倒也无所谓
What does the A stand for? Not that it matters.
没错 因为从现在起就是Heidi E.了
No, because now it'll be Heidi E.
Heidi Eckersberg
Heidi Eckersberg.
那好吧
All right, then.
噢不 才刚有起色
Oh, no! Just as things were working out.
为什么要打断
Why this break?
更别提这个简陋无谓的变焦了
Not to mention this primitive, pointless Z O O M?
我要宣布 没有打断就不是喜剧
I declare, no comedy without breaks.
不管多不情愿 维生素是必须要打的
Vitamins must be injected, however reluctant we are.
谁愿意做拿着针筒的医生
And who likes being the doctor with his syringe.
来打断孩童的嬉戏呢
interrupting a child's play?
没错 就是我了
You're right. Yours truly.
在这里 我感到有义务 引入一个新角色
And I hereby feel obliged to introduce a new character.
老板饥渴得要死
The boss is horny as hell.
他可能身上还有
There's probably still a slight trace
那么一点基
of homophilia in his dong.
老板这就来找你了
The boss will be right with you.
这一句说服力怎么样 宝贝
How was the cred in that line, toots?
不赖嘛 "宝贝"
Not bad, "toots."
Kisser 你不做IT的啊
Kisser! You don't work with IT.
你不也是吗
The same goes for you.
我记得没见过你这么高兴
I don't remember you looking this happy.
但我们也只结过5年婚而已 还是50年
But we were only married for 5 years. Or was it 50?
你有高兴过吗
Were you ever happy?
有 对着那个甘比尼流口水的时候
Yes, when drooling over that Gambini jerk.
一个谁也没听说过的骗子
A hoax nobody's ever heard of.
伟大的骗子 在甘比尼那儿 灾难已经发生了
A hoax in seven-league boots. With Gambini, disaster has already struck.
单幕剧 三个小时 "烟囱工的独白"
A one-act play, three hours long! The Chimney Sweep's Monologue!
太狄更斯了不适合我
Too much Christmas Carol for my taste.
- 怪不得我受不了你 - 我也受不了你
- No wonder I couldn't stand you. - I couldn't stand you, either.
为什么
Why not?
花生
Peanuts.
你带着皮一起吃 只有动画片里才那么干
You ate them with the shells on. They only do that in cartoons.
让我发疯
It drove me crazy!
我猜你来这里有事
I bet you're here to get something.
来挽回我的
Come to win me back?
我才不想挽回你
I don't want you back.
那就是别的事了
For something else, then.
你他妈那么高效
You're so damned efficient.
我猜你还没入学就毕业了吧
I bet you graduated even before you started.
我是Finnur Sigurdsson的代理律师
I'm Finnur Sigurdsson's attorney.
哇 资本主义
Wow, capitalism!
你不是该用学位跟他们做斗争的吗
Weren't you going to use your degree to fight it?
是 我也这样想
Yes, I believe I was.
Finnur提过我 但你忘了
Finnur mentioned me, but you forgot.
生活就像道格玛电影 那些话很难听清楚 但仍然很重要
Life is a dogma film. It's hard to hear, but the words are still important.
我是来评估 总裁明天会不会来
I'm here to assess the likelihood of the president's presence tomorrow,
和我的客户谈判的
at the sales talks with my client.
目前我很怀疑 我只知道你不是他
So far, I have my doubts. All I know is you're not him.
为什么我不能是 为什么我就不能是大老板
Why couldn't I? Why couldn't I be the boss of it all?
就像《没有烟囱的城市》里的烟囱工吗
Like the chimney sweep from The Town without Chimneys?
- 额头总带着煤灰 - 也许你错了
- Always with soot on his forehead. - Maybe you were wrong.
也许当初是你小看我了呢
Maybe there is more to me than you saw back then.
是啊
Yes.
但是我没有 有吗
But there isn't, is there?
没有
No.
根据法学院教的那些来看 是没有
Not according to what they teach at law school.
我们教的比这实际
What we learnt was more tangible.
他到底是总裁 或者不是
Is that really the president, or isn't he the president?
好吧 我是个替身
All right, I'm a stand-in.
我不能说 我签了保密协议
My lips are sealed. I signed a non-disclosure agreement.
和Ravn的保密协议
A non-disclosure with old Ravn?
妈的 Kristoffer
Dammit, Kristoffer!
你栽在他手里了 他是个合同高手
He's really got you by the balls. He's a whiz with contracts.
你要去拆我的台吗
Are you going to blow the whistle on me?
那十年前你开始演戏的时候 我就已经去了
Then I'd have done it ten years ago when you started acting...
宝贝
toots.
- 但我看你挺喜欢这个角色 - 我很擅长
- But I see you love the part. - I am good at it.
是啊
Seems so.
况且有你的角色可不容易
And parts for you don't exactly grow on trees.
而且考虑周全也不是你的性格
And it goes against your convictions to check things thoroughly.
你只想引人关注
All you want is attention.
是我管住这些技术宅
I keep these IT nerds in check.
这样真正的老板才能做生意
So that the rightful owner can do business.
我们法律界说 "蠢得无法形容"
In law we say, "Too stupid for words."
说的就是你 要是你相信Ravn的话
And that's you, if you believe Ravn.
Ravn还不错 我们挺好的
Ravn is all right. We get along fine.
他爱他的员工 但他不是做老板的料
He loves his staff, but lacks the strength to be the boss.
他是个懦夫 但不是坏人
He's a wuss, but not malicious.
除非他利用这一套 极尽所能驱使他的员工
Not unless he exploits the system to drive his staff to the utmost.
把一切都怪到老板头上 你就能受人喜欢和尊敬了
By blaming all the shit on this boss you can appear likable and noble.
你干嘛关心
Why do you care?
我不关心
I don't.
但我一度在你身上 还看出一点正派
But once I saw a shred of decency in you.
你没你想的那么坏 Kristoffer
You're not as bad as you'd like to be, Kristoffer.
你像是差点就考虑过道德因素了
You almost looked like you considered the moral aspects.
Ravn做的一切对公司都是有利的
All of Ravn's dealings benefit the company
因此对员工也是
and thereby his staff.
对于让他们喜欢工作 是件好事
This is a good deal for their beloved workplace.
也许 既然Ravn像你以为的那么高尚
Possibly. And since Ravn is as noble as you perceive him to be,
我想 他一定告诉过他的员工 他们喜欢的工作
I'm sure he has told his staff that their beloved workplace
就是明天要交易的主角
is the subject of tomorrow's deal.
Ravn要把公司卖掉
Is Ravn selling the company?
是 就这么简单
Yes. Simple as that.
不 你没有
No, you didn't.
你没有利用我
You didn't manipulate me.
你一向很绅士
You've been quite the gentleman.
即使是在我差点就要跳槽去敌对公司那时
Even when I almost quit to work for our worst competitor.
你痛斥过Ravn几次
You've laid into Ravn a  few times.
他看着有点难过 接完你的电话之后
He's looked a bit sad after a phone call from you.
好啦
Well...
我得下去了
I have to pop down...
复印点东西
to make some copies.
有谁感到被利用了吗
Does anyone else feel manipulated?
我没有 但是Gorm有
Not me, but Gorm does.
那次是个严重的打击
That was a serious blow.
你为了Brooker平台那件事否决了他的时候 他很受打击
He took it hard when you overruled him on the Brooker platform issue.
他已经在另一个平台上花了两年了
He'd spent two years  on the other platform.
你怎么能在Brooker的事上也发号施令 那是我们的
How can you even dictate things concerning the Brooker? It's ours.
我倒没有 但Nalle有 你太过分了
Not me, but Nalle does. You were out of line.
你说他从来不做准备
You told him he never came prepared.
然后大家都开始说他 你清楚他会失控
Then everyone started in on him. You knew he'd snap.
嗨 我能用英语问你个问题吗
Hi. Can I ask you a question in English?
丹麦语
Danish.
- 我们用英语吧 - 不 丹麦语
- Let's do it in English. - No, Danish.
你撤了他的丹麦语课 这样他就没法在走廊里说闲话了
You took away his Danish lessons so he couldn't gossip in the corridors.
他就不能用英语说闲话吗
Couldn't he just gossip in English?
当然能 但他不想
Sure, but he didn't want to.
至于我 除了让我关照Ravn以外 没有
And me... Not apart from making me see to Ravn.
但那也不是对你有利
But that didn't benefit you.
Ravn呢
What about Ravn?
我们可爱的小熊
Our cuddly teddy bear?
你没法不爱他 尽管有时他有点可怜
You can't help loving him. Although he's pathetic at times.
可能我不该提 但他的经济状况一团糟
Maybe I shouldn't mention it, but his personal finances are a mess.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
他说的
He said so.
差不多最早时 后来我们讨论决定每人借他两万五
Mostly at first. Then we discussed it and decided to lend him 25,000 each.
倒也没帮上什么
Not that it helped.
为什么
Why not?
他现在也没还我们呢
He hasn't paid us back yet.
- 再就是可怜的Mette了 - 是
- And there's Poor Mette. - Yeah.
你知道你裁掉他丈夫之后怎么了吗
You know what happened after you sacked her husband?
不 我想不知道
No, I don't think so.
他上吊了
He hung himself.
用一根打印机线 他受不了被排除在外
With a printer cable. He couldn't take being excluded.
他求着回来 Ravn讲了他给你写的信
He begged to let him come back. Ravn told us about the letters he sent you.
但我们没他的位置
But we had nothing for the guy.
是 这就是生活
No, that's life.
- 然后现在她就成了可怜的Mette - 她在哪里
- And now she's Poor Mette. - Where is she?
在复印室 我猜
In the copy room, I guess.
- Elisabeth 打印机开着吗 - 是的
- Elisabeth, is the copier working? - Yes.
那边
There.
一派胡言
It's pure fantasy.
谣传总是有的
There has to be some rumors.
我创办了公司 一点功劳是应得的
I deserve a bit of goodwill for starting the business.
那15万股份可不是他们出的
They didn't stake the 150,000.
正是他们
That's exactly what they did.
他们都借了你钱 然后你用来开了公司
They all lent you money, and you used it to start the company.
- 我知道这看着有点可疑 - 当然了
- I know it looks a bit shady. - It sure does!
我才是导演 你只是演员
I'm the director, you're just the actor.
有没有关系得问你的角色
Ask your character if the pieces fit.
我问了 恐怕有
I did, and I'm afraid they do.
我要真是这么个混蛋
If I'm really such an asshole
他们也最好卖掉 就能摆脱我了
they're better off selling, so they're rid of me.
我们得签订代理权
We have to sign the power of attorney.
我规定了底价 这样你就不能卖得更低
I've stipulated a minimum price so you can't sell for less.
Kristoffer不可通过贱卖来愚弄Svend
Kristoffer shouldn't put one over on Svend by selling for a buck.
- 我不该留一份吗 - 要是你坚持的话
- Don't I get to keep one? - If you insist.
我不比任何人更好或更坏
I'm no better or worse than anyone else.
- 我不确定 - 我觉得饱受误解
- I'm not so sure. - I feel so misunderstood.
我付出再付出 得到了任何回报吗
I give and give. Do I get anything in return?
太少 太少
Rarely, rarely.
2亿5千4百万 可不是小钱
254 million. Not exactly peanuts.
斯特林堡也被人误解了
Strindberg was misunderstood, too.
人们总在谈论
People were always talking.
说他把妻子推下了楼梯
They said he pushed his wife down the stairs.
- 但他没有 - 当然有
- And he didn't? - Sure.
但这不耽误他是个大作家
But that doesn't make him any less of a writer.
账户号也写在这里了 很方便嘛
The account number is there, too. Very handy.
这样我们的北欧朋友就不用到处拖着现金了
So our Nordic friends won't have to lug that cash around.
那不是账号 是价格
It's not the account number. It's the price.
那应该远远足够了
That should more than cover it.
那是你的公司的估值 先生
That's the estimated value of your company, sir.
我们签字吧
Shall we sign?
这里
There...
我要请您注意一下
May I draw your attention to
几处我把文本简化了的地方
a couple of places where I've simplified the text?
关于员工们不会留任的条款
The clause about the staff not staying on.
好的 我完全信任你
Fine. I trust you completely.
员工们会留下的 对吗
The staff will stay on, right?
我们说好的不是这样的
That's not what we agreed.
我们才不会忍受一堆该死的丹麦佬
We're not getting stuck with a bunch of fucking Danes.
Ravn先生是唯一会留下的雇员
Mr. Ravn is the only employee who will stay on.
我还去掉了几个逗号
I also took out a couple of commas
移交Brooker5的专利权 从持有人Ravn先生那里
on the transfer of the Brooker 5 patent from its owner, Mr. Ravn.
其他的持有人会得到什么呢
What do the other rights holders get?
什么也没有
Nothing.
Ravn先生有独占权
Mr. Ravn has the sole rights.
那六个高管认为他们也有权利
The six seniors think they have rights, too.
情感上 也许吧
Emotionally, maybe.
但法律上 没有
But legally, no.
他们做了工作 但那是他们的职责
They worked on the program, but that was their job.
打扰一下
Excuse me for a moment.
透透气就好
Some fresh air might be good.
非常感人
It's all very touching,
但你什么也改变不了
but you can't change anything.
要是不卖给Finnur 我会再找一个买家
If I don't sell to Finnur, I'll find another buyer.
而且你不能通过贱卖来坑我
And you can't screw me by selling cheaper.
来吧
Come on.
总裁先生
Mr. President.
好了 我们签吧
All right. Let's seal the deal.
- 也该签了 - 是的
- About time, too. - Yes.
得离开这一切了 让我很难过
It's rather sad to have to part with all of this.
但是Ravn先生清楚 我心底是个生意人
But as Mr. Ravn knows, I'm a businessman at heart.
那就赶紧做生意
Then let's get down to business.
我真的喜欢上这里了
I have really grown fond of this place.
我几年以来的这个舞台
It's been my stage for quite a few years now.
好想法 但是已成历史 我们还有合同要签
Lovely thoughts, but it's history. We have some contracts to sign.
谢谢 Ravn 你总能帮上忙
Thanks, Ravn. Always so helpful.
乐意效劳
At your service.
就签这里
Sign right there.
我把手挪开 你就能赶紧签了
I'll move my finger so you can get on with it.
你同意吗 Finnur先生 Ravn先生很有帮助
Don't you agree, Mr. Finnur? Mr. Ravn is very helpful.
我才不像你们矫情的丹麦式多愁善感
I don't share your soppy Danish sentimentality.
- 就差签字了 - 是的
- All that's left is to sign. - Yes.
给打印合同的律师提个醒
A note to the lawyer who typed up the contract.
把页码放在文字中间是个坏主意
Putting the page number in the middle of the wording is a bad idea.
我不知道在你们冰岛是怎么干的
I don't know how you do things in Iceland...
那不是页码
It's not the page number.
是购买价
It's the purchase price.
我这份上标的居然是2亿5千4百万
My copy states the ridiculous sum of 254 million.
那是我们商量好的 他妈的
That's what we agreed on, for fuck's sake.
我不能把毕生心血这样就卖掉 你理解的
I can't sell my life's work for that. Surely you understand.
总裁想把公司卖多少钱
How much does the president want for his company?
再高些
More than that.
高多少
How much more?
5毛
50 cents.
纯粹是象征性的
It's purely symbolic.
作为一个生意人 我喜欢觉得自己有钱赚
As a businessman, I like to feel I have profited.
我们说着自由意志 但其实听从心里的机器
We talk of free will, but we heed the machine within.
渴望金子的机器
The machine that wants gold.
咔嗒 咔嗒
Ticktock, ticktock...
有时候一点点碎渣就能解饿
Sometimes a mere crumb can satisfy the hunger.
我们得重打合同了
We'll have to retype the contracts.
我们可以手动改掉
We can amend them by hand.
我知道这是个生意人的争辩
I know it's a  businessman's argument.
但是 我要是能多要5毛
But, if I can get 50 cents more...
那我就能多要5千万
then I can get 50 million.
Finnur先生
Mr. Finnur?
Finnur
Finnur!
就在那里
There it is!
"没有烟囱的城市" 一直就在那里
The Town without Chimneys. It's been there all the time.
一瞬间全都聚齐了
Everything comes together for an instant
只等着在一场甘比尼式的爆发中被炸成碎片
only to be blown to bits in a Gambinian explosion.
不幸的是 我们这个小喜剧不是总提到的那个甘比尼写的
Sadly, the oft-mentioned Gambini did not pen our little comedy.
他的轻蔑会把类型扭曲得认不出来
His contempt would have distorted the genre beyond recognition.
不 我是服从类型的法则的
No. I obey the laws of the genre.
不管两个人互无所求的景象有多美好
However beautiful the sight of two men asking nothing of each other.
我们清楚人们彼此有所要求
we know there are men who demand things of each other.
而且这些要求必须在我们离开影院之前得到满足
And these demands must be met before we can leave the cinema
然后心安理得地忘掉看过的一切
and with a clear conscience forget everything we've seen.
- 你他妈为什么不签字 - 嘘
- Why the fuck didn't you sign?! - Shh.
我听懂了
I understand your question.
噢 真的吗 那可是一大笔钱
Oh, really? It's a lot of money.
你气死我了
You piss me off!
- 我受够你的脾气了 - 你要开除他们
- I'm sick of your moods.
- You're firing them.
你故意不说 你要把他们掏空
You neglected to say that. You're robbing them blind.
Brooker5 不管那是什么玩意
Brooker 5, whatever that is.
你气死我了
You piss me off.
你是公司的律师
You're the company lawyer
而且是他们的朋友
and their friend.
你该告诉他们他们需要合同的
You should have told them they needed contracts.
他们根本没想到过会丢掉工作
They don't even suspect they're losing their jobs.
- 是有点残忍 - 可不是吗
- It's a bit harsh. - No shit.
我们快点办完了吧
Let's just finish the deal.
那正是我的想法
That was the whole idea,
但我愿意做点妥协
but I'm willing to make a trade-off.
说清楚 告诉他们你要裁掉他们
Confess! Tell them you're sacking them.
我保证
I promise.
我不相信你
I don't trust you.
你一直在糊弄我
All you've done is trick me.
签了这个保证 说清楚你要开除他们 夺走他们的权利
Sign this promise, confessing you're firing them and taking their rights.
我能做的都做了
I have done what I could.
我不爱签东西
I'm not thrilled about signing something.
想法就是上帝 你说的 就算作者是希特勒
The idea is God. You said so yourself. Even if Hitler was the writer.
当时 我并不知道作者就是希特勒
At the time, I didn't know the writer was Hitler.
你要是真打算说清楚 就签了它
If you're serious about confessing, then sign it.
还得有最高价 以防你再耍花样
And a maximum price, to stop you pulling these stunts.
- 那边闭上嘴 - 嘘
- Shut up down there! - Shhh.
今天
Today...
是沉重的一天
is a very grave day.
我决定告诉你们点事
I have decided to tell you something
我几年前就该告诉你们了
I should have told you ages ago.
我做不到
I can't do this...
你不用非得说
You don't have to say it.
让他说吧
Let him get on with it.
是 我得说
Yes, I do.
是谁从不让我们失望
Who never lets us down?
Ravn
是谁的肩膀借我们哭泣
In whose arms do we drown?
Ravn
Ravn's
桂冠应当颁给谁
Who deserves the crown?
Ravn Ravn Ravn
Ravn, Ravn, Ravn...
你们都太好了 这样只会更糟糕
You're all so sweet. It just makes it worse.
要是真那么重要 就赶快说了吧
If it's really important, just get it over with.
你们会生气的
You'll be angry.
你不说我们更生气
We'll be angrier if you don't.
我一直在计划着
I've been planning something.
嗯 计划着什么
What have you been planning?
把你们六个开除
To fire all six of you.
什么
Excuse me?
把你们开除 没有任何Brooker5的补偿
To fire you without any compensation for Brooker 5.
真是个好计划
That's quite a plan.
妈的 Ravn
Dammit, Ravn.
- 妈的 Ravn - 妈的
- DammitRavn. - Dammit.
- Ravn 妈的 - 妈的
- Ravn, dammit. - Dammit.
妈的 Ravn
Dammit, Ravn!
天杀的
Holy shit.
在我们攻击Ravn之前 我想问个问题
May I pose a question before we all attack Ravn?
为什么计划这个 Ravn 为什么开除我们
Why did you plan this, Ravn? Why fire us?
- 为什么把Brooker5从我们这骗走 - 因为
- Why cheat us out of Brooker 5? - Because...
嗯
Yes?
因为
Because...
大老板说的
The boss of it all said so.
我就该知道
I should've known.
他甚至没胆量自己告诉我们
He didn't even have the guts to tell us himself.
- 秋天真是阴郁 - Gorm
- Autumn is muggy. - Gorm...
- 秋天真是阴郁 - 停下吧
- Autumn is muggy. - Stop it.
秋天
Autumn is...
真他妈
fucking...
阴郁
muggy!
Gorm 停下
Gorm! Stop it!
我到底没胆量
I didn't have the guts after all.
他们会记住
They've got memories
就像
like...
据说大象的记忆能保留数十年
大象
Elephants?
对
Yes.
对 我晚上躺下 眼前就看到他们的眼睛
Yes. I lie awake at night. I see their eyes before me.
原谅 你说
Forgiveness, you say!
他们永远不会原谅我
They'll never forgive me.
可怜的Mette最严重
Poor Mette is the worst.
我说什么对她都不够
Nothing I say is good enough for that girl.
我真是个懦夫
I'm such a wuss!
要是你不坦白他们没法原谅你
They can't forgive you if you don't confess.
我们有合同
We had a contract.
"我保证坦白"
"I promise to confess."
谁签的字
Who signed?
我坦白了我的计划
I confessed to my plan.
然后告诉他们是我强迫你的 那不是坦白
And told them that I forced you! That's not a confession.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
为什么合同上不说
Why didn't the contract say so?
你的不幸 法律是极其精确的学科
Unfortunately for you,law is an extremely exact science.
因此我要求
And therefore I demand
你尊重你签的合同 卖掉
that you honor the contracts you have signed, and sell.
我跟Finnur安排了最后一次会面
I've set up one last meeting with Finnur.
你不想露面来上班
You don't want to show your face at work.
所以我告诉他们你在美国
So I've told them you're in the States
直到签合同那天
until the day of the signing.
嗨 是我 我们得见个面
Hi. It's me. We have to meet.
在外面
On neutral ground.
嗯
Mm!
法律上 你动不了他 他抓住你了
Legally, you can't touch him. He's got you.
你不得不卖
You have to sell.
- 真是悲哀 - 是啊
- It's a total downer. - Yes.
但他差点就坦白了 对吗
But he almost confessed, right?
你有种存心在精神上折磨别人的本事
You have a knack for deliberate mental cruelty.
你说得对
You're right.
但我更擅长无心地惹恼别人
But I'm better at being irritating on an intuitive level.
他最怕的是什么
What's his greatest fear?
没人爱 这就是一切的关键
Not being loved. That's what it's all about.
他想做一个
He wants to be the...
惹人爱的大玩具熊 不然他就会崩溃
big, cuddly teddy, otherwise he loses it.
抢走他那个惹人爱的玩具熊的位置
Take his place as the cuddly teddy bear.
像Ravn一样做 只是做得更好
Do what Ravn did. Only better.
嗯
Mm!
早上好
Good morning.
你好呀
Hello there.
你们这儿有位置给我这个小不点吗
Do you have room for tiny little me?
Ravn
Ravn!
来和我们一起
Won't you join us?
越多越开心
The more the merrier.
- 我们以为你在美国 - 是的
- We thought you were in the States. - Yes.
我本该在
I was supposed to be.
但我尊敬的美国朋友随时都能见
But I can see my valued U.S. buddies any time.
但我最宝贵的朋友们
But my most invaluable friends...
我只有
I have only
两天可见了
two more days with.
- 对吗Ravn - 对
- Right, Ravn? - Yes.
在家庭的怀抱中还有两天了
Two more days in the bosom of the family.
- 秋天真是个气象学噩耗 - 是的
- Autumn is a meteorological bombshell. - Yes.
说到噩耗 我有点事要坦白
Speaking of bombshells, I have a confession to make.
上一次搞得有点激烈了
Things got a bit heated last time.
但等我告诉你们 我其实是为什么才来
But when I tell you why I really came,
你们会发现 你们误解我了
you'll see you were wrong about me.
- 你是个混蛋 - 很可能
- You're a bastard. - Quite possibly.
但是也许不是你们想的那样
But maybe not the way you think.
我一直对你们隐瞒着信息
I've been withholding information from you.
这下可好多了
That makes everything much better.
哇 谢了 我们原谅你
Gee, thanks, we forgive you.
我不是单独行动来着
I haven't been acting alone.
有人在后台
There has been someone in the wings.
这个人应当走到台前了
This person deserves to be brought out into the light.
在在我上面的人
It's someone above me.
我的上司 我的老板
My superior, my boss.
有点复杂
It's getting very technical.
而那个人是
And who might that be?
是
It is...
大 大老板
...the boss of the boss of it all.
现在可真的复杂起来了
Now it's getting really complicated.
谁能告诉我这是什么意思吗
Can anybody tell me what this means?
不
No.
所以这个大大老板在哪里
So where is this boss of the boss of it all?
在美国 毫不意外
In America. No surprise there.
所以你不是做决定的那个真的老板
So you're not the real boss who makes the decisions?
这点上 我也得让Jokumsen失望了
I've had to disappoint Jokumsen on that point, too.
他所有的怒火和指责必须得 就像你们一样
All his anger and reproaches must, like yours,
找个新对象了
find a new target.
听到这个我很高兴
I'm glad to hear it.
你还不错 Svend
You're all right, Svend.
我一下就看出来了
I could tell right away.
这种事我们乡下人清楚
We hicks have to know these things.
作为老板的代表
As the boss' representative,
请允许我为了Brooker平台的事道歉
allow me to apologize for the Brooker platform business.
因为你们一直是对的
Because you were right all along.
你没法不爱他 对吧
You can't help loving him, right?
还有为了进一步鼓舞士气
And to raise our spirits even more...
到库伦的全体出游定在明天
The staff outing to Kullen  is set for tomorrow.
- 太好了 - 我们一起开心一下
- Great! - Let's have one fun day together.
一起来个大拥抱怎么样
How about a big group hug?
来吧Ravn
Come on, Ravn!
- 来吧Mette - 上 可怜的Mette
- Come on, Mette! - Go, Poor Mette!
你有什么目的
What are you hoping to achieve?
没什么 我们只是开开心
Nothing. We're just having fun.
到这里了 就是这里
Here we are! Right here!
帕尔纳托克：丹麦的传奇海盗英雄
哈拉尔一世：10世纪丹麦国王
帕尔纳托克 对哈拉尔一世 吹嘘 他滑雪多么厉害
Palnatoke bragged to Harald Bluetooth about how great a skier he was.
"你要是那么厉害 就从这里滑到库伦"
"If you're that great, ski down the Kullen from here."
- 然后他就滑了 就在这儿 - 然后呢
- And he did, right here. - Then what?
呃 我没往下读了
Eh, I didn't read that far.
人为失误 你会进步的
A human fault. You're evolving.
而现在
And now...
现在帕尔纳托克要来证明 他独一无二的趿拉板滑雪术了
And now Palnatoke will demonstrate his own unique Telemark style!
嗷
Ouch!
你的手怎么了
What's with your hand?
是我的手腕 又开始麻了
It's my wrist. It's gone... limp again.
怕是旧病复发了
I'm afraid it's a relapse.
我们很快解决它
We'll soon fix that.
康复最快的那人
The most resilient of men
Svend
我们最亲爱的新朋友
Our new-found dearest friend
Svend
十次中有十一次
Eleven out of ten
Svend Svend Svend
Svend, Svend, Svend
请再来点白兰地
More brandy, please!
我受不了了
I can't take it anymore.
一群寄生虫
What a bunch of parasites!
我要告诉大大老板
I'm telling the boss of the boss of it all.
你们他妈是怎么浪费他的钱的
The way you're wasting his money.
妈的
You disgust me!
你已经找到突破口了
You've found a crack.
他极其老套 不夸张地说
He is extremely corny, to put it mildly.
所以你需要的是老套剧目
So you need corny theater.
你之前还不够低级
You haven't been aiming low enough.
客厅剧务实主义 多愁善感
Living-room realism, sentimentality...
陈词滥调
Clichés.
陈词滥调 陈词滥调 陈词滥调
Clichés, clichés, clichés.
你要来吗
Are you coming?
到时间了
It's time.
来吧
Come on.
你们为什么开会
Why are you at the meeting?
因为
Because... boss...
大
Boss...
因为大老板
Because... boss of it all...
- 因为大老板说的 - 对
- Because the boss of it all said so. - Yes.
We'll be in our cars five minutes from now.
这次我们达成共识了吗
Do we agree this time?
是的
Yes.
价格和条款都是
On the price and terms?
是的
Yes.
- 我们签吧 - 是
- Let's just sign. - Yes.
既然一切都定了 让我说点话
And because everything is settled, allow me to send a message...
这些日期全错了
These dates are all wrong.
太丢人了
How embarrassing!
我会改正 对不起
I'll correct them. Sorry.
说点话
...a message.
在Titi姨妈和Carl姨父的婚礼上
At Aunt Titty and Uncle Carl's wedding anniversary...
礼金存入了一个旧袜子里
a collection was made in an old sock.
但我们一直存入了每一天 整整十年
But here we've been collecting every single day for ten years.
就在这里
Right here.
等到了Titi姨妈和Carl姨父
The day came for Aunt Titty and Uncle Carl,
就像我们一样
as it will for us,
他们的派对结束的时候
when the party is over.
有天早晨醒来 伸出手
We wake up one morning and put out our hands...
抓到的
...and all we grasp
只有空气
is thin air.
而你
And you,
而我
and me,
而我们彼此
and the two of us,
这三者
these three people
就仅仅只是一段史诗
are but a saga.
你 曾是我的生命的那个人
You, who were once my very life,
而我 对你也曾如此
and I, who was once yours,
将永远不会再携手
shall never again hold hands.
而这些话是对谁讲的
And to whom is this message addressed?
那个总是第一个咒骂自己的错误
The man who is always the first to curse himself for his mistakes,
却第一个原谅我们的错误的人
but the first to forgive us ours.
我说的是谁
Who do I mean?
- Ravn - Ravn
- Ravn.... - Ravn...
大声点
Louder!
- Ravn - Ravn
- Ravn. - Ravn.
你把我们放在心里 Ravn
You carried us in your heart, Ravn.
你团结了我们
You brought us together.
你无私地给出你的爱
You gave generously of your love.
而现在你要走了
And now you're going away...
就像海里的泡沫
like bubbles in the bay.
走向更伟大的事业
On your way to greater deeds.
但有一件事我们保证
But one thing we promise.
不管失意还是得意
Whether begging or biting,
不管咫尺还是天涯
Whether near or far,
你的家将永远
your home will always be
在我们心里
in our hearts,
这个绿洲
in this green and pleasant land.
总是 我们总是有你在
Always. You were always there for us.
但是他妈的 你又有谁
But, dammit, who was there for you?
记着 在燕子在屋檐下叽喳的此时
And know this, as the swallow twittered beneath the eaves,
这是再见 不是永别
this is not adieu, but au revoir!
感谢你的话 但愿说完了
Thanks for your words. May they be the last.
感谢矫情得这么肉麻
Thanks for sentimentality so nauseating
以至于任何生物都不可能当真
that no living creature could possibly take it seriously.
你有什么要说的吗 Ravn先生
Do you have something to say, Mr. Ravn?
有什么我们
Is there anything
忽视了的吗
we have overlooked?
请讲 Ravn先生
Do tell us, Mr. Ravn.
我就是大老板
I'm the boss of it all.
公司是我的
I own the company.
决定是我做的
I make the decisions.
Gorm说得对
Gorm is right.
他说得对 秋天真是阴郁
He is right. Autumn is muggy.
真是阴郁
Real muggy.
阴郁得令人作呕
Gaggingly muggy.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 谢谢你 Ravn - 谢谢你 Ravn
- Thank you, Ravn. - Thank you, Ravn.
真有那么难讲吗
Was it really so hard to say?
我一直都知道你就是老板
I always knew you were the boss.
你真是傻才会看不出来
You'd have to be stupid not to see that.
我原谅你 Ravn
I forgive you, Ravn.
来吧
Come on.
站起来 起来啦
On your feet... Upsy-daisy.
站直
All the way.
那签字呢
What about that signature?
你是要卖 还是怎样
Are you going to sell, or what?
这有点难办
That might be tricky.
Kristoffer怎么卖掉从来不属于他的东西呢
How can Kristoffer sell what's never been his?
不 Sigurdsson先生
No, Mr. Sigurdsson.
不卖了
There will be no sale.
公司现在
The company is
比任何时候都团结
more strongly united than ever.
等我纠正了过去的一些过错 会更团结
And more so, when I've put right a few sins of the past.
我有些外移要检查
I have some offshoring to see to.
外包
Outsourcing!
那个词是外包 你说外移 应该是外包
The word is outsourcing. You said offshoring. It's outsourcing.
你现在正在做的 就是我最气的
What you're doing right now is what irritates me the most.
你忘记了演员
You're forgetting the actor.
你说得对 对不起
You're right. Sorry.
能让我坦白全亏了Kristoffer
Kristoffer deserves the credit for making me confess.
- 一切都是因为你 - 那可真好
- Everything's due to you. - That's all very well.
但不是这样的
But that's not how it works.
你不能一下从地狱跳到"从此幸福地在一起"
You don't just jump from hell to happily-ever-after.
有些形式必须得走
There are certain formalities that have to be kept.
你说得对 Kristoffer
You're right! Kristoffer!
我们现在就废除这些该死的合同
Let's annul these fucking contracts right now.
你就免除卖掉公司的代理权了
And now you just waive the power of attorney to sell the firm.
不
No.
什么
What?
不
No.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
有些约束性承诺是
There are binding commitments that
是你不能一挥笔就废除的
you can't annul by the stroke of a pen.
我们对交易不再感兴趣了
We are no longer interested in a deal
既然很清楚 执笔的人
since it's clear that the man with the pen
并不是公司的合法所有者
is not the company's legal owner.
从读过的史诗中 我的客户知道
From his reading of the sagas my client knows
与配角商谈者 一事无成
that he who deals with stooges deals with nobody.
我们的客户刚想起来
Our client just remembered
有些新的典籍
some new scriptures
指出了一种更现代的解读
that indicate a more modern interpretation.
更合适的翻译是
More appropriately rendered:
"与没有授权的人商谈 一事无成"
"He who deals with a man without power of attorney deals with nobody."
在我们的客户看来 执笔的人
As our client sees it, the man with the pen
确实具备授权
is indeed furnished with power of attorney
他没意见
and that's fine with him.
怎么回事 Kristoffer
What's going on, Kristoffer?
这正是你想要的结果
It worked out like you wanted.
是 差不多
Yeah, more or less.
你不是想签吧
You're not thinking of signing!
这不归我管
It's beyond me.
我是个演员
I'm an actor.
我签还是不签
Whether I sign or not
取决于我的角色
is up to my character.
我得问问他
I'll have to ask him.
- 但你的角色就是罪魁祸首 - 是的
- But your character is to blame for all this. - Yes.
这可能只是个形式
It's probably just a formality.
我需要空间
I need space
来咨询一下我的角色
to consult my character.
毕竟
After all
他才是大老板
he is the boss of it all.
怎么回事
What's going on?
他在作对 他是个演员
He's being contrary. He's an actor.
他受不了让Ravn吸引了所有的关注
He couldn't stand it when Ravn got all the attention.
他只是在装模做样 既然每个人都在看着他
He's just putting on a show, now that everyone is looking at him.
我希望是
I hope...
等等
Hang on a moment.
我联系不上了
I can't make final contact.
我好像听到老板在说什么
I seem to hear the boss saying something.
然后又可能是相反的话
And then it might be the opposite.
后面安静点
Silence in the back!
嘘
Shh!
你得把你的素材变成活人
You have to breathe life into your material.
你的角色的道德观是什么
What are your character's moral values?
太迷人了
It's fascinating.
让我实话实说
And let me be completely frank...
我一点线索还没有
I haven't the slightest clue.
有同情也有反感 试图相互抵消
There are sympathies and antipathies, trying to cancel each other out.
我只能再听听
I'll just listen some more.
我知道了
I got it.
死里逃生
Close call
同情的指针
but the sympathy meter needle
想方设法偏向了Ravn和他的员工这一方
just managed to sway in favor of Ravn and his staff.
你们该死该死该死的丹麦佬
You shitty, shitty, shit-faced Danes.
你们该死的唠叨
With all your damned chatter.
你们折磨了我们400年
You gave us 400 years of torment.
这个白痴到底是签还是不签
Is the idiot going to sign or not?
我唾弃丹麦民族
I abhor the Danish race.
最后一句是什么
What was the last thing?
他说整件事太荒谬了
He said the whole business was absurd.
荒谬得就像是
As absurd as...
甘比尼
Gambini.
Gambini?
安东尼奥·斯塔夫罗·甘比尼
Antonio Stavro Gambini?
《挨饿的猫》 单幕剧 1969
The Hanged Cat. One act, 1969.
有些人说是1968年末
Some say late 1968.
我操
Oh, shit.
别想了
Forget it.
是甘比尼
It's Gambini.
烟囱工的独白
The chimney sweep's monologue.
就这样我们到达了 就在濒临放弃之时
And so we reached, on the verge of giving up.
到达了我们的喜剧的结尾
the end of our comedy.
和你一样 我想回家
Like you. I would like to get home,
但我要道个歉 对那些还嫌少的人
but I'd like to apologize to those who wanted more
还有那些嫌多的人
and those who wanted less.
那些得其所想的人
Those who got what they came for,
活该
deserve it.
字幕译校&压制 @舌尖要越舔越形而上